{
    "id": "70b5b8a1394f4eeaa0b6f53145bbd09e",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercis",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "When I reached the station, the train ……………….. already ………………….",
            "description": "The past perfect is used to show that one action had completed before another action commenced. ",
            "answers": [
                "is, gone",
                "has, gone",
                "had, gone"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you know why …………………………….. angry with me?",
            "description": "In indirect questions, the auxiliary verb goes after the subject. ",
            "answers": [
                "is she",
                "has she",
                "she is"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I couldn’t help …………………………. when I saw his funny hairstyle.",
            "description": "The ing form is used after couldn't help...",
            "answers": [
                "laughing",
                "laugh",
                "to laugh"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "By the end of this week, he ……………………………… his work.",
            "description": "The future perfect is used to say that an activity will have completed by a certain point of time in future. ",
            "answers": [
                "will finish",
                "would finish",
                "will have finished"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "As the population grows, the demand for resources ……………………………..",
            "description": "Use simple tenses in both clauses to talk about two situations that develop simultaneously. ",
            "answers": [
                "increase",
                "increases",
                "is increasing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She won’t finish it ……………………………. tomorrow.",
            "description": "Either till or until is possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "till",
                "until",
                "up to"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The two girls quarrel with ………………………… whenever they meet.",
            "description": "Use each other to talk about two people or things. ",
            "answers": [
                "one another",
                "each other"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It is no use …………………………. with her.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to argue",
                "arguing",
                "to arguing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………….. you marry, make sure that he is loyal to you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Whoever",
                "Whomever",
                "Whichever"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………… we went, we found the people friendly.",
            "description": "Wherever means it doesn't matter where. ",
            "answers": [
                "Wherever",
                "Whatever",
                "Whichever"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………………. cold it is, he always goes swimming.",
            "description": "However cold means it doesn't matter how cold it is.",
            "answers": [
                "Though",
                "As",
                "However"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Bring me the book …………………………….. is on the table.",
            "description": "Either which or that is possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "what",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}